## **RESUME**

## PERSONAL INFORMATION

NAME David Alexander Rueda Ramírez

BIRTH PLACE Bogotá–Colombia EMAIL davrueda@gmail.com

GRADUATION WORK Definition of UML Profiles for the analysis, development and easy

maintenance for Applications P2P under the JXTA platform.

#### **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

The graduates of the Systems Engineering Program at the University of Cauca engineer can perform satisfactorily as project manager of information systems at the various companies generating products and services, as a researcher in interaction with other disciplines, such as design and implementation engineer information processes, as a consulting engineer and consultant for products and services related to the computer industry and as administrator of the units responsible for supporting information within businesses.

Systems Engineer graduated from the Universidad del Cauca will be able to provide solutions to the optimal management and Information Management within a systematic and mechanized process that involves not only the availability of the means by which it takes place (data, actions, measurements), but also compliance with standards and specifications, appropriate interaction between the components of the process and of these with the environment, to meet the needs for the benefit of the institutions, the region and the country.

Specialist in Web Application Development in Java J2EE, JavaScript, JSP, Ajax, Struts and Hibernate through My Eclipse IDE, Net beans. Experience in web application development in PHP on apache application server and MySQL database

#### **EDUCATION**

#### PROFESSIONAL STUDIES

PREGRADO UNIVERSITY OF CAUCA

Title: Engineer of System 2008

Line Research: Internet Technologies, Information Technology Networks Peer to Peer (P2P),

Geographic Information Systems, SOA, Service Delivery.

Popayán, Colombia.

SECUNDARY COLEGIO NACIONAL SUCRE

Title: Bachelor Academic Ipiales (Nariño)–Colombia

July 1 de 1997

## INVESTIGATIVE REFERENCE

## **GRADUATION WORK**

Definition of UML profiles for modeling and construction of telematics SOA Services for P2P applications.

## TECHNICAL KNOWLEDGE

CASE TOOLS - Rational XDE Power Designer

RationalRose98y2000
MicrosoftVisio2003
Enterprise Architect
Magic Draw UML

DATABASES - Oracle9.x.

- PLSQL-Dev.

- MicrosoftSQLServer2005

- MySQL

Postgres pl-sql SQL Manager 2007

**SYBASE** 

Microsoft ISQL/w

## **OPERATING SYSTEM**

- Linux, Ubuntu 9.04
- WINDOWS9x/2000/XP/Vista/7

OFFICE - Microsoft Office 97/2000/XP/2003/2007/

# PROGRAMATION LANGUAGES AND OTHER TOOLS

- Microsoft Visual Studio 2005.NET
- J2EE
- JEE
- J2ME
- C#
- C/C++
- Java
- JavaScript
- Action Script
- PROLOG
- PHP
- Netbeans-5.0/5.5/6.0/6.8
- Eclipse3.x, Europe
- Ice faces, Spring
- Swish ax Flash
- Apache Tomcat, JBoss, Weblogic-OAS
- Send Studio
- Myeclipse8.x hibernate3.x
- Ajax
- Jsf
- Web Sphere Integration DeveloperV7
- Maven
- GIT
- Jenkins
- Spring Boot
- Spring tool Suit

## GOOGLE CLOUD

- Compute Engine
- Kubernetes Engine
- App Engine
- Cloud Functions
- Storage (Cloud DataStore, Cloud Spanner, Cloud Storage)

## GEOGRAPHIC INFORMATION SYSTEM

- ArcGIS Server
- ArcGIS Desktop (ADF) en .Java- ArcMap, ArcView, ArcCatalog

IBM

- Web Sphere Application Server6.0
- Web Sphere Integration Developer 7.0 BPM
- -Rational Application DeveloperV7
- -Web Sphere Tool Kit BrokerV8
- -IBM DataPower GateWay 7.5
- -IBM MQ
- -IBM Integration BUS 10

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

- IBM Certified Solution Developer WebSphere Message Broker V8.0
- Scrum Developer SEONTI

## COURSES, EVENTS AND SEMINARS

#### **ASSISTANT**

Microsoft Developer Day .NET Technologies

Académico2005GiraAndina

Academic

University of Cauca Popayan–Colombia

Mayo31de2005.Duración5horas. Seminary

III Seminary International Technologies Internet 2004

SITI200

Technologies Internet

University of Cauca. Popayan Colombia.

Octubre7, 8 y 9 de 2004.

Duración24horas

Microsoft Developer Day Academic 2004 Gira Andina

Academic

Tecnologías.NET

University of Cauca Popayan–Colombia Septiembre17de2004. Duration: 5 hours.

Quality of Software University of Cauca

SegundoPeriodode2004 Esp. Julio Ariel Hurtado <u>ahurtad@unicauca.edu.co</u>

Applications WEB University of Cauca

First Period 2006 Esp. Javier Hurtado javhur@unicauca.edu.co

Development de Applications

ClienteInteligenteen.NET

University of Cauca First Period 2006

MSc. Carlos Cobos ccobos@unicauca.edu.co

Seminary

Seminary

Course

Course

Application Development University of Cauca For Mobile Devices First Period 2006

Esp. Oscar Mauricio Caicedo-omcaicedo@unicauca.edu.co

Esp. Javier Hurtado-<u>javhur@unicauca.edu.co</u>

Computer Security University of Cauca Course

Second Period 2006 Ing. Siler Amador Donado samador@unicauca.edu.co

#### OTHER PARTICIPATIONS

I Seminar Organizer Process Improvement

III Seminar Organizer Internet Technologies International

University of Cauca.

Internet Popayán Colombia.

October 7, 8 y 9 de 2004.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

Bogotá, Colombia

Cargo: Technical Architect

Functions: Architect SOA Integration, JEE Analyst, Google Cloud Developer, Analyst e Implementation of services IBM WebSphere Message, distribute work, ensure the quality of the deliverables, provide production support, development tests, train new developers, propose improvements in the development process, propose points for improvement. Febrero 2019

### AYESA

Bogotá, Colombia Cargo: Technical Lead

Functions: Analyst SOA Integration, JEE Analyst, Analyst e Implementation of services IBM WebSPhere Message

BROKER.

Febrero 2018 – 2019

#### SOPHOS BANKING

Bogotá, Colombia

Cargo: Senior Technical Consultant

Functions: Analyst SOA Integration, JEE Analyst, Analyst e Implementation of services IBM WebSPhere Message

BROKER.

Febrero 2014 - 2018

#### **COBISCORP COLOMBIA**

Bogotá, Colombia

Cargo: Senior Developer Analyst SOA-JEE-Sybase

Functions: Analyst Developer JEE application requirements, analysis and implementation of mediation

flows with IBM Web Sphere Message BROKER 7.

Immediate Supervisor: Maria Isabel Peña

December 2 0 2011

#### **OESIA COLOMBIA**

Bogotá, Colombia

Cargo: Senior Java Developer Analyst authorized to ATH

Functions: Implementation and maintenance of new functionalities in the banking business system for

different Aval group entities

Immediate Supervisor: Javier Estrada

June 2 0 2011

## INDRA COLOMBIA

Bogotá, Colombia

Cargo: Analyst Developer Java / Oracle

Functions:

- Java Development, Application Maintenance Support Block Telephonic Movistar such as Credit Management System implemented in ADF / ORACLE, Control-M, Report Builder.
- BPM Workflow Development in Web Sphere 6.0, Basic Management Application Server Web Sphere Application Server 6.0

Immediate Supervisor: Doris Amparo Ortega

June 17 2010 - June 17 2011

#### GML Ltd.

Functions: Java Development Lead - Ice faces, spring, Hibernate-IDE

Bogotá, Colombia

Project manager: Juan Pablo González C. Cargo:

February 2010-Junio 2010

#### SYNERSIS Ltda.

Bogotá, Colombia

Project manager: Veronica Fernandez Position: Java Developer Analyst Postgres

Functions: Financial Development module in the Java language and interfaces AJAX, and analysis and development of stored procedures

March 2007 - January 2010

#### **ACADEMIC REFERENCES**

#### PHD JUAN CARLOS VIDAL

Associate Professor.

Systems Engineering Program.

Faculty of Electronics and Telecommunications.

University of Cauca. Popayan, Colombia.

Phone: 57-2-8209800 Extension 2117

#### MSc. JULIO ARIEL HURTADO ALEGRIA

Associate Professor.

Systems Engineering Program.

Faculty of Electronics and

Telecommunications.

University of Cauca.

Popayan, Colombia.

Phone: 57-2-8209800 Extension 2117.

## MSc. Eliana MARTHA MENDOZA

Systems Department Head.

Faculty of Electronics and Telecommunications. University of Cauca. Popayan, Colombia. Phone Extensión2149 2-8209800.

DAVID ALEXANDER RUEDA RAMIREZ 7177323 de Tunja